Contact

9826423503 (Home) tiwariankur77@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/tiwariankur77 (LinkedIn) reachankur.in/ (Personal)

Top Skills

JavaScript HTML SQL

Languages

English (Professional Working)
Hindi (Native or Bilingual)
Sanskrit (Professional Working)

Certifications

CutShort Certified Laravel Learn Angular 5 from Scratch Shaping up with Angular.js CutShort Certified PHP Blasting Off With Bootstrap

Ankur Tiwari

Laravel | Php | React | MEAN | AWS | Technical Head @ Gyrix TechnoLabs

Madhya Pradesh

Summary

I'm Technology Head at Gyrix, your software development partner. I've been working with many startups and established companies throughout my years in the IT. I've learned to outline and fulfill their needs and demands. Since then it has been my personal focus: how to select professionals, assemble and manage remote teams, build project-oriented work processes and adjust them to the businesses of the clients I worked with, and make regular timely deliveries.

I believe that ideas and passion mean as much. The people I work with have plenty of great ideas that we make tangible. These people stir up real mini-revolutions in their industries – and I believe in them. Their products make the life of end users easier and better – and it inspires me. I am fully dedicated to mutual trust and success, teamwork, long-term collaboration, and the importance of what we do together.

Wanna get in touch? Drop me an email on tiwariankur77@gmail.com

Experience

Gyrix TechnoLabs Head Of Technology March 2020 - Present (8 months)

Indore, Madhya Pradesh

- 1. Develop technical aspects of the company's strategy to ensure alignment with its business goals
- 2. Discover and implement new technologies that yield competitive advantage
- 3. Help departments use technology profitably
- 4. Supervise system infrastructure to ensure functionality and efficiency
- 5. Build quality assurance and data protection processes
- 6. Monitor KPIs and IT budgets to assess technological performance
- 7. Use stakeholders' feedback to inform necessary improvements and adjustments to technology

Communicate technology strategy to partners and investors

Basecamp Startups India

Team Lead

June 2018 - March 2020 (1 year 10 months)

Indore Area, India

- 1. Guide team development efforts towards successful product delivery
- 2. Provide technical leadership to teammates through coaching and mentorship
- 3. Collaborate with other software developers, business analysts and software architects to plan, design, develop, test, and maintain the web and desktop-based business applications.
- 4. Analyze and resolve technical and application problems.
- 5. Adhere to high-quality development principles while delivering solutions on time and on a budget.

MaalGaadi

2 years 2 months

Chief Technology Officer

May 2017 - May 2018 (1 year 1 month)

Indore Area, India

- 1. Lead development activities including deploying continuous integration systems, architecture, technologies & processes.
- 2. Contributed to the team's internal infrastructure by improving the process, seeding-in optimized workflows, team morale, hiring, etc.
- 3. Served as a technical adviser for company-wide strategic matters
- 4. Found and coordinated with external technology vendors in the areas of procurement, software development and on-premise support.

Team Lead

April 2016 - May 2017 (1 year 2 months)

Indore, Madhya Pradesh, India

- 1. Create an inspiring team environment with an open communication culture
- 2. Set clear team goals
- 3. Delegate tasks and set deadlines
- 4. Oversee day-to-day operation
- 5. Monitor team performance and report on metrics
- 6. Motivate team members
- 7. Discover training needs and provide coaching
- 8. Listen to team members' feedback and resolve any issues or conflicts

- 9. Recognize high performance and reward accomplishments
- 10. Encourage creativity and risk-taking
- 11. Suggest and organize team building activities

Gyrix TechnoLabs LLP Software Developer September 2014 - April 2016 (1 year 8 months) Indore, Madhya Pradesh, India

- 1. Worked closely with business stakeholders to understand their requirements, & identify opportunities to improve business processes through outstanding web development.
- 2. Built scalable web-based applications that meet rigorous standards for usability, security & conformance to a variety of platforms and screen sizes.
- 3. Lead front-end web development throughout the planning, design and development lifecycle for many unique and innovative user experience projects.

Indore Informatics
Software Developer
September 2012 - September 2014 (2 years 1 month)
Indore

- 1. Worked with the senior developer to manage large, complex design projects for corporate clients.
- 2. Developed project concepts and maintain optimal workflow.
- 3. Completed detailed programming and development tasks for front-end public and internal websites as well as challenging back-end server code.
- 4. Collaborated with designers to create clean interfaces and simple, intuitive interactions and experiences.
- 5. Carried out quality assurance tests to discover errors and optimize usability.

Education

Malwa institute of Technology, Nipaniya Byass, Indore Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Computer Science (2010 - 2014)

New Father Angle H. S. School High Secondary, Science · (2005 - 2010)